let pythonquestions = {
    time: 30, // in minutes
    questions: [
        {
            question: "1. What is the output of the following code snippet: print(2 ** 3)?",
            option1: "6",
            option2: "8",
            option3: "4",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "8",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "2. What is the keyword used to define a function in Python?",
            option1: "func",
            option2: "def",
            option3: "function",
            option4: "define",
            correctresponse: "def",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "3. How do you create a list in Python?",
            option1: "list()",
            option2: "[]",
            option3: "{}",
            option4: "()",
            correctresponse: "[]",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "4. Which of the following is the correct syntax to output the type of a variable?",
            option1: "print(type(variable))",
            option2: "print(variable.type())",
            option3: "print(variable.type)",
            option4: "print(type of variable)",
            correctresponse: "print(type(variable))",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "5. What will be the output of the following code snippet: print('Hello' + ' ' + 'World')?",
            option1: "Hello World",
            option2: "HelloWorld",
            option3: "Error",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "Hello World",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "6. What data type is the object below: x = 'Hello'?",
            option1: "String",
            option2: "Integer",
            option3: "Float",
            option4: "List",
            correctresponse: "String",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "7. How do you create a comment in Python?",
            option1: "// Comment",
            option2: "/* Comment */",
            option3: "# Comment",
            option4: "// this is a comment",
            correctresponse: "# Comment",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "8. What will the following code print: print(10 // 3)?",
            option1: "3",
            option2: "3.33",
            option3: "0",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "3",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "9. Which of the following functions is used to find the length of a list in Python?",
            option1: "len()",
            option2: "size()",
            option3: "length()",
            option4: "count()",
            correctresponse: "len()",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "10. What is the default value of an argument in a function?",
            option1: "None",
            option2: "0",
            option3: "False",
            option4: "'' (empty string)",
            correctresponse: "None",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "11. What does the 'break' statement do in Python?",
            option1: "Exits the loop",
            option2: "Continues to the next iteration",
            option3: "Exits the program",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "Exits the loop",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "12. Which of the following is used to handle exceptions in Python?",
            option1: "try-except",
            option2: "try-catch",
            option3: "error-handler",
            option4: "catch-finally",
            correctresponse: "try-except",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "13. How do you create a dictionary in Python?",
            option1: "{}",
            option2: "[]",
            option3: "dict()",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "{}",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "14. Which of the following will give an error in Python?",
            option1: "x = 10 + 2",
            option2: "x = 10 / 0",
            option3: "x = 5 * 3",
            option4: "x = 100 - 50",
            correctresponse: "x = 10 / 0",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "15. What is the output of the following code snippet: print('5' * 3)?",
            option1: "15",
            option2: "555",
            option3: "Error",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "555",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "16. How do you define a variable in Python?",
            option1: "var x = 5",
            option2: "x := 5",
            option3: "x = 5",
            option4: "5 = x",
            correctresponse: "x = 5",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "17. Which of the following is the correct syntax to import a module?",
            option1: "import module_name",
            option2: "include module_name",
            option3: "use module_name",
            option4: "import(module_name)",
            correctresponse: "import module_name",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "18. What will be the output of the following code: print([1, 2, 3] + [4, 5])?",
            option1: "[1, 2, 3, 4, 5]",
            option2: "[1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6]",
            option3: "Error",
            option4: "[1, 2, 3]4, 5",
            correctresponse: "[1, 2, 3, 4, 5]",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "19. Which operator is used to compare two values for equality in Python?",
            option1: "==",
            option2: "=",
            option3: "===",
            option4: "!=",
            correctresponse: "==",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "20. What is the output of print(bool('False'))?",
            option1: "False",
            option2: "True",
            option3: "Error",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "True",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "21. What type of object is returned by the input() function in Python?",
            option1: "String",
            option2: "Integer",
            option3: "List",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "String",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "22. How do you check if a key exists in a Python dictionary?",
            option1: "key in dictionary",
            option2: "dictionary.contains(key)",
            option3: "dictionary.has(key)",
            option4: "key.exists()",
            correctresponse: "key in dictionary",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "23. What does the 'continue' statement do in a loop?",
            option1: "Exits the loop",
            option2: "Skips the current iteration and proceeds to the next one",
            option3: "Stops the program",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "Skips the current iteration and proceeds to the next one",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "24. How do you remove an item from a list in Python?",
            option1: "remove()",
            option2: "del()",
            option3: "pop()",
            option4: "All of the above",
            correctresponse: "All of the above",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "25. What does the zip() function do in Python?",
            option1: "It joins two lists together",
            option2: "It creates a list of tuples from two lists",
            option3: "It compresses a list",
            option4: "It sorts a list",
            correctresponse: "It creates a list of tuples from two lists",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "26. What is the purpose of the pass statement in Python?",
            option1: "It is used to exit a loop",
            option2: "It is used as a placeholder for future code",
            option3: "It stops the program",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "It is used as a placeholder for future code",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "27. Which of the following is an immutable type in Python?",
            option1: "List",
            option2: "Dictionary",
            option3: "String",
            option4: "Set",
            correctresponse: "String",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "28. How do you define a class in Python?",
            option1: "class MyClass()",
            option2: "class MyClass",
            option3: "MyClass class",
            option4: "def MyClass()",
            correctresponse: "class MyClass",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "29. What does the 'self' keyword represent in Python?",
            option1: "The current object",
            option2: "The current function",
            option3: "The current class",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "The current object",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "30. How can you concatenate two strings in Python?",
            option1: "Using + operator",
            option2: "Using * operator",
            option3: "Using concat() function",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "Using + operator",
            time: 1,
        }
    ]
};

export default pythonquestions;
